[Music]
i am finally back home just in time for
the beginning of the harvest season
it's incredible how much my valley
changes from spring to summer
luscious greens and abundant meadows dry
out into crisp prairies of bitterroot
and sage
[Music]
during my trip i made the decision to
disconnect from technology as much as
possible
i thought i'd share some ways that i use
technology and social media to benefit
me
instead of weighing down my mind or
demotivating me
which happens i find if i use it too
much
since i recently made a video on this
topic i thought i'd expand into more
practical ways i enrich my reality so
that the world in my phone seems far
less important in regards to who i am
and how i spend my time
[Music]
one very simple way i disconnect is by
finding ways to incorporate more
movement in my days
walking somewhere stretching using my
phone for example often leaves me very
stationary and affects my posture and
neck if i'm hunched over too much
by looking at my phone less i notice so
many more things specifically the sky
if you have the chance right now i would
encourage you to take a quick moment and
run outside and look up the enormity of
the sky is always wondrous and makes you
feel small in the best way
there is so much out there more than we
will ever discover and it really puts
things into perspective
if an image or comment or anything at
all is bothering me it suddenly seems so
inconsequential
and i really feel silly for wasting
precious time over it
the same is true for the insecurities
that often arise from comparison
it offers so little benefit and if
anything it distracts you from the
beauty of your own existence
there is so much to experience in this
world and within your spirit i wouldn't
waste one more minute over something so
small
[Music]
another way i disconnect is by still
actually using technology but just using
it differently i find music and certain
sounds incredibly calming and centering
i also love listening to stories and
watching movies that inspire me and
looking at art
in these ways i disconnect from the
noise and notifications and messages and
yet still can cultivate richness in my
life through exposure to so much art and
ideas
[Music]
since being online more i've noticed
people often recommend silent meditation
as a means to feel more centered when
the world seems hectic
i respect anyone who can meditate for a
long time and am happy to know how much
it benefits some people
but i have never been able to do it
i live in a very quiet environment for
the most part so meditation actually
feels a little weird when in a rural
area everything is already so still
[Music]
my way of meditating and being in touch
with myself is through movement my hands
need to move and create and cook my mind
needs to have something to focus on like
written words or music or ideas
it is when i'm my most creative that i'm
also most at peace
i find that through this i strengthen my
spirituality
i encourage you to find your best way to
meditate as i don't think any specific
form works for everyone
meditation isn't limited to sitting in a
room if anything i find that especially
if you're not very active meditation
through movement be it walking or hiking
or even dance
can have as much benefit depending on
who you are
whatever makes you feel most at ease and
creative
[Music]
another way i disconnect is by not
fearing boredom this feeling has an
incredible ability to inspire you with
new ideas and interests and hobbies
[Music]
um
so
[Music]
lastly i always try to reserve my
evenings as a time free of unwanted
distractions i may watch a movie listen
to a book or music while i do some
tidying around my home
it is a very special time for me and i
particularly enjoy lighting candles
i recently discovered this adorable
small business inspired by mythology and
fantasy and i wanted to briefly mention
how much i enjoy their candles i'll
leave their website down below they're
perfect for lovers of storytelling books
fairies and imagination this is of
course not sponsored i just really love
these candles and wanted to share them
with you
i hope you have a wonderful day or night
and i will see you next week
sending my love
[Music]
my
shhh
[Music]
you